# **ADITYA MANKAR**

Los Angeles, CA | 602-727-8653 | aditya.mankar94@gmail.com | www.adityamankar.com | www.linkedin.com/in/adityamankar/

# **SUMMARY**

A 5-year **experienced software** engineer, proficient in C++, Python, and developing enterprise applications. Among **1% of university** students who demonstrated advanced research skills and **system design** expertise by defending Master's thesis at the intersection of distributed systems (Blockchain) and sustainable resource trading

## **RESEARCH EXPERIENCE**

## **California State University Long Beach**

Los Angeles, CA

**Research Assistant** 

May 2022-August 2023

Tech Stack: JS, AWS EC2, React, NodeJS, Solidity

- Conducted original research, under former Dean of University, critically analyzing over 50 research papers to uncover repeating
  patterns in existing platforms and developed distributed system architecture by investing over 1000 hours
- Authored a paper on the Decentralized Energy Trading Framework, scheduled for publication in 2 months
- Conducted in-depth research on Load Balancing Algorithms, unveiling a 25% performance enhancement in Round-Robin, credited to the strategic application of game theory

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**Scientific Games Corporation** 

July 2016-October 2021

**Senior Software Engineer** 

Tech Stack: C++, Git, OpenGL, Game Engine

- Led a team of 4 people to execute new game concepts, collaborating with cross-functional teams to gather requirements and specifications, and creating modular component-based timeline. Implemented real-time multiplayer functionality using TCP and UDP socket programming
- Trained and **mentored** 3 junior game developers through hands-on guidance, adding new training modules, and adding SOLID coding principles into the tasks to improve first game development time by 1 week
- Pioneered a complex feature-merging issue, ensuring seamless integration and **overcoming ambiguity**. Devised a core logic of a feature that encapsulated deprecated features, conceptualizing around 40% of future development standards and guidelines
- Innovated a new reliable design review framework of iterative Proof-of-Concept, that conceptualizes feature design and development, increasing visualization. This promoted precise requirement specification and a reduction in bugs by 25%

# **Software Engineer**

Tech Stack: C++, Python, SQL, Git, Jira

- Diagnosed Electronic Gaming Machines (**Embedded machines**) specific procedures and released a new modular workflow that made debugging fast and precise, improving task estimation and reduced the game review timeline by 3 days
- Eliminated 30% of internal game review bugs by introducing a 'review developer' role, streamlining development practices and common issues. This led to a 1-week reduction in the overall SDLC timeline.
- Engineered novel way to integrate object pooling mechanism in animations, optimizing size of graphic-intensive games by 20%

## **PROJECTS**

## **Order Matching System**

Los Angeles, CA

Tech Stack: C++, Design Patterns

- Developed a robust order-matching system by implementing 3 different design patterns to enhance order creation, and trade execution, ensuring efficient order matching
- Integrated logging mechanism, improving root-cause analysis process and streamlined workflow

#### Website Deployment (www.adityamankar.com)

Los Angeles, CA

Tech Stack: AWS S3, EC2, CDN, Docker, Jenkins

• Deployed static website developed in HTML, CSS, and JS onto Amazon S3 server and later migrated to **Amazon EC2** services to understand the feasibility options and flexibility. This involved server management intricacies, understanding performance optimization, implementing **CDNs**, and setting up **Docker** and Jenkins for **CI/CD pipelines** to automate development workflows

#### **SKILLS**

Proficient: C++, Python, System design, Slot games, Blockchain

Intermediate: JavaScript, React, NodeJS, SQL, NoSQL, API, Flask, HTML, CSS, Solidity

Technology & Framework: AWS S3, EC2, CDN, Serverless, Kubernetes, Docker, Jenkins, Git, Jira, Design Patterns

#### **EDUCATION**

California State University Long Beach Masters of Science in Computer Science Los Angeles, CA

August 2021-August 2023

India

August 2012-May 2016

Savitribai Phule Pune University
Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science